David Frisk

$\textbf{Video Editing} \cdot \textbf{Motion Graphics} \cdot \textbf{3D} \cdot \textbf{Software Engineer} \cdot \textbf{Web Development}$

734.846.2075 Dearborn, MI david@friskypixel.net friskypixel.net

Profile

Although primarily a Video Editor, I have the ability and experience to touch nearly all aspects of post-production. From motion graphics and 3D, to color correction and audio, I regularly take part in fulfilling all roles necessary for a job. I also have a background in Computer Science, with experience in Web Development and Software Engineering, allowing me to wear many hats and contribute to a wide range of tasks. I am a strong believer in life-long learning, and there's never a time where I don't strive to either learn something new or more fully master my primary job.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Apr 2022 - Jun 2023

ARRAY Remote

- Worked with a small team of engineers using the Svelte framework in conjunction with Typescript to help build, maintain and customize the front-end of embeddable web components.
- Created custom themes for clients based on Figmas, design guides and branding, as well as made specific functionality and behavior changes that were requested.
- Helped in the development of our custom internal Theme Editor tool that allowed for a GUI-based, user-friendly experience theming our clients, contributing to the reduction of deployment times.
- Assisted in the implementation of a localization framework across our entire codebase, allowing for the addition of new language and customization options.
- Regularly assisted in code reviews.

SENIOR LEAD VIDEO EDITOR / WEB DEVELOPER May 2013 - Dec 2021

TWEDDLE GROUP Clinton Twp, MI

- Edited Owner Information videos for clients that included FCA, Mazda Europe, Nissan and Infiniti North America/Canada/Mexico, in over 20 language using the Adobe Creative Suite.
- Developed the front-end of the company website from scratch using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and the Bootstrap framework.
- Took on additional tasks, including creating Access databases, setting up customerfacing webinars, and creating marketing campaigns utilizing Mailchimp.

VIDEO EDITOR May 2007 - Apr 2013

COMMUNICORE Troy, MI

- Edited award-winning long-format, commercials and corporate videos for a variety of clients using Avid Media Composer, with accompanying motion graphics created with Adobe After Effects, Photoshop, and Illustrator.
- Winner of 2010's D Show Award: The Best of the Craft, for editing "Audi: 100 Years" video.

MANAGER OF TRANSCRIPTION / TRANSCRIBER Jul 2004 - Feb 2007

"DR. PHIL" - CBS PARAMOUNT Hollywood, CA

 Lead a team who transcribed interview and B-Roll footage for Editors to use in show segments, collaborating with Segment Directors and Producers on needed material.

POST-PRODUCTION ASSISTANT Jan 2007

"BLONDE AMBITION" - SONY PICTURES / MILLENNIUM FILMS Hollywood, CA

 Organized all incoming dailies material including script notes, shot logs, camera reports, etc.

ASSISTANT EDITOR Apr 2006 - May 2006

"STARTING OUT IN THE EVENING" - INDIGENT. Hollywood, CA

- Set up and maintained projects and workspaces for the Editor, as well as all of the backups.
- Organized and tagged all shots and audio in order to provide a more efficient editing workflow.
- Edited some portions of the film's audio and sound effects.

VISUAL EFFECTS ASSISTANT Nov 2005 - Apr 2006

"CHARLOTTE'S WEB" - PARAMOUNT / NICKELODEON Hollywood, CA

- Handled all incoming visual effects shots and distributed them to appropriate departments.
- Gathered and turned over shot information and data to vendors.

POST-PRODUCTION ASSISTANT Feb 2005 - Sep 2005

"THE EXORCISM OF EMILY ROSE" - SONY SCREEN GEMS Hollywood, CA

 Maintained organization of the department, coordinating between post-production members, directors, producers and others in the delivery of various paperwork, screeners, and other materials. Created temporary visual effects for early screenings of the film using Adobe After Effects.

VIDEO EDITOR Oct 2003 - Jun 2004

CVMEDIA Northville, MI

• Began part-time as an assistant helping out with live events, DVD/tape replications and transfers, and other various office tasks, before becoming a full-time editor, cutting various corporate videos.

Education

UDACITY 2021

Nanodegree in Front End Web Development

Certificate - https://confirm.udacity.com/UD5E9ZVJ

WAYNE STATE UNIVERSITY Detroit, MI; 2011-2013

Computer Science, 4.0

- Selected to Golden Key International Honor Society, 2012
- Awarded John P. Stieber Endowed Scholarship, 2012
- High Scholastic Average Award for a Junior, 2012 / Senior, 2013
- Placed on Dean's List during entire duration

FULL SAIL UNIVERSITY Winter Park, FL; 2002-2003

Associate of Science in Film, 4.0

- Valedictorian
- Perfect Attendance

LAWRENCE TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY Southfield, MI; 2000-2002

Computer Science, 3.67

- Awarded Academic Scholarship, 2000
- Placed on Dean's List during entire duration

Skills

Video: Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Avid Media Composer, Blender, Cinema 4D

Development: HTML, CSS/SCSS, Javascript, Typescript, Svelte, React, Git/Github/Gitlab, Bootstrap, Playwright, Node.js, WordPress